Vitaliy Utkin

Web Developer utkin.vitaliy@gmail.com • www.linkedin.com/in/vitaliyutkin

I offer more then 14 years of professional hands-on experience in Web development. I design, implement and maintain modern Web applications where availability and performance are paramount. I have established myself as a full-stack JavaScript developer with a bias towards front-end.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Oracle East Central Europe Services

2018 — Current

JavaScript Developer, Principal Applications Developer

As a part of Nextweb Platform team I've created dozens of tools and services used by other dev teams as well as third-party developers:

- Created UI libraries used across organization
- Designed and implemented JS SDK used by our customers
- Maintained and improved tons of existing solutions our team own with full tests and documentation coverage

Beetroot Resources

2014 - 2018

Front End Developer

Implemented various projects for the client working in healthcare industry:

- Migrated old-fashioned healthcare portal to modern front-end technologies from scratch
- Created web tools and services for custom hardware devices
- Lead a squad of two front-end developers

eBay Inc. 2011 - 2014

Front End Developer

Building new eCommerce Magento 2 platform:

- Was part of a team that launched a brand-new, fully-featured eCommerce platform
- Implemented Core UI library and templates for new platform, created migration guides and documentation
- Implemented Magento Connect service, which is marketplace for new platform

EDUCATION

Master of Computer Science

2001 - 2007

Odesa I. Mechnykov National University, Ukraine

SPECIALIZATIONS

JavaScript, React, Redux, NodeJS, UX, modern CSS/HTML, SPA, Cypress, StoryBook, Webpack, Git, CI/CD tools (Jenkins)